<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tools>
	<item>
		<picture>uhrglas.jpg</picture>
		<name>Watchglass</name>
		<desc>Watchglasses are round glass panes with a diameter of around 5 - 10cm, used in various experimental techniques. The border is bent upwards to allow the watchglass to hold small amounts of liquids in order to let them evaporate. The evaporation can be accelerated by heating the watchglass with a Bunsen burner. Watchglasses can also be used to cover Petri dishes or beakers, and are also suited to weighing small amounts of matter or drying them in an airing cupboard. The term watchglass is derived from the former pocket watches' protection glass which was often domed.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>exikator.jpg</picture>
		<name>Dehydrator</name>
		<desc>A dehydrator is a piece of laboratory apparatus, often made of glass, and which serves to dry chemical matters; that is, to remove water or liquid from a sample.
			In principle it is a glass bowl with cap that has a planar grinding, so that the bowl is air-tight. The dehydrator's lower part is ordinarily filled with a drying agent such as calcium chloride, silica gel, phosphoric anhydride or sulphuric acid. The sample to be dried is placed on a diaphanous cartridge of plastic or ceramic above the drying agent.
			The drying agent is hygroscopic, which means that it dehumidifies its environment by absorbing water vapor. The dry atmosphere then takes up water from the sample to be dried.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>spatel.jpg</picture>
		<name>Spatula</name>
		<desc>The spatula is a laboratory tool to scrape off, grind, and transport chemicals. The material they are made of (e.g. iron, titanium, platinum) and their design (e.g. flat spatula or spoon spatula) varies.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>wasserstrahlpumpe.jpg</picture>
		<name>Water Jet Pump</name>
		<desc>The water jet pump has two entry pipes and one exit, and consists, in principle, of two pipes one inside the other. At the water entry a water jet shoots under full pressure out of a nozzle into a slightly larger pipe. The water jet thereby carries away air or fluid from the second entry. &lt;br&gt; This is caused by the negative pressure in a drifting fluid, and thus it is an application of the hydrodynamic paradox (objects close to drifting fluids are aspirated instead of being pushed away).</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>brechungsmesser.jpg</picture>
		<name>Refractometer</name>
		<desc>With a refractometer the refractive index of optical media is determined. If the refractive index of a chemical is known it can be used after a synthesis to determine the sample's purity or to audit the synthesis' success.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>moerser.jpg</picture>
		<name>Mortar</name>
		<desc>A mortar is used for manually grinding solids. It can also be used to homogenize a mixture of powders by grinding. A club-shaped tool known as a pestle is used with the mortar for grinding.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>heizplatte.jpg</picture>
		<name>Heating Coil</name>
		<desc>Heating coils are used to heat flasks and other containers. Multiple heating coils can be connected with a thermometer so that the heat will not exceed a specified temperature. It is possible to use a magnetic field inside the heating coil to stir fluids with a magnetic stirrer. This will homogenize the fluid in terms of temperature and composition.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>korkring.jpg</picture>
		<name>Cork Ring</name>
		<desc>Large containers like round-bottomed flasks are placed on rings made of cork, a special soft lightweight wood with good insulating qualities to protect fragile instruments.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>tropftrichter.jpg</picture>
		<name>Dropping Funnel</name>
		<desc>A dropping funnel can be used to drop precise amounts of fluid. The dropping speed can be controlled with a valve.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>scheidetrichter.jpg</picture>
		<name>Separating Funnel</name>
		<desc>A separating funnel can be used to separate a mixture of fluids of differing densities. A valve at the bottom allows the denser fluid to be drained for transfer to another container.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>rg-staender.jpg</picture>
		<name>Test Tube Rack</name>
		<desc>This rack is useful when many small amounts of chemicals are to be tested in a row; or alternatively, to dry test tubes.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture></picture>
		<name>Vortexer</name>
		<desc>A vortexer serves to homogenize reagents found in laboratories. The container containing liquid to be homogenized is put on a platform. The platform shakes by rotary agitation up to 3000RPM at which point a contact sensor is activated. In this way extremely small volumes of fluid can be homogenized quickly. It is the opposite of a centrifuge, used to separate fluids.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>spritzflasche.jpg</picture>
		<name>Wash Bottle</name>
		<desc>These bottles are used for many purposes. In most laboratories they are usually filled with water, salt, acid or other commonly used fluids. They make it easy to apply the fluid if a precisely measured amount is not needed.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>rotationsverdampfer.jpg</picture>
		<name>Rotary Evaporator</name>
		<desc>A rotary evaporator consists of a round flask in a bath of hot water, and is designed to evaporate solvents. The flask is rotated and the solvent collects under a vacuum onto a condenser and drips into a condensate collecting flask. In this way solutions can be concentrated or purified. By attaching a vacuum pump, the air pressure and therefore the boiling point of the fluid can be decreased.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>rueckflusskuehler.jpg</picture>
		<name>Reflux Condenser</name>
		<desc>A reflux condenser subjects fluid to a process where a gas produced by heating is collected on the reflux condenser. The fluid is cooled until it condenses and runs back into the original fluid. Usually it is put on a round-bottomed flask or several neck flasks.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>pileusball.jpg</picture>
		<name>Pipette Bulb</name>
		<desc>A pipette bulb is used to fill pipettes. Squeezing then releasing the bulb produces a negative pressure, causing fluid to flow into the pipette; squeezing the bulb then causes the fluid to flow out of the pipette.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>rg.jpg</picture>
		<name>Test Tube</name>
		<desc>In a test tube small reactions or experiments are performed. There are many different types of tubes. For example some have connectors, some are etched for measurements, some are hardened for durability.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>schutzbrille.jpg</picture>
		<name>Protective Goggles</name>
		<desc>Most laboratories insist that protective goggles are worn. Without them, it is too risky to work with most chemicals. Usually, the lens is a special type of plastic that affords protection from both mechanical impacts, and acid and base chemicals.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>rundkolben.jpg</picture>
		<name>Round-Bottomed Flask</name>
		<desc>A round-bottomed flask is used for many reactions. Some can be connected to other items, as the frosting on the neck shows. With cork rings they can be placed on a table.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>vollpipette.jpg</picture>
		<name>Full Pipette</name>
		<desc>Unlike a regular pipette, a full pipette only has one marking for a specific volume.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>trockenrohr.jpg</picture>
		<name>Drying Tube</name>
		<desc>Some reactions need to be kept free of water: to make this possible a drying tube can be used. Drying tubes contains a hygroscopic chemical to absorb water from the atmosphere.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>rg-halter.jpg</picture>
		<name>Test Tube Holder</name>
		<desc>Test tube holders make it easier to hold test tubes. By using a holder, there is a safe distance between ones hand and the test tube when the tube is hot. Typically, test tube holders are used to hold test tubes over open flames.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>messzylinder.jpg</picture>
		<name>Measuring Cylinder</name>
		<desc>A measuring cylinder can be used to measure amounts of liquids relatively precisely. Furthermore, the cylinder allows particulate matter to sink: following this, the particulates can be separated from the fluid by decanting.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>thermometer.jpg</picture>
		<name>Thermometer</name>
		<desc>A thermometer can be used to determine the temperature of a sample. In a laboratory, special thermometers are used which can also be used within acids or bases.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>ruehrfisch.jpg</picture>
		<name>Magnetic Stir Bar</name>
		<desc>Magnetic stir bars are highly chemically inert, small magnetic bars. Most heaters have a built-in magnet which can rotate: this causes the stir bar to rotate and the mixture to become homogenized.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture></picture>
		<name>Magnetic Stir Bar Retriever</name>
		<desc>A magnetic stir bar retriever can be used to retrieve magnetic stir bars from containers. The retriever is a bar with a magnet at the end which attracts the stir bars.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>pipette.jpg</picture>
		<name>Pipette</name>
		<desc>Pipettes are used to introduce small quantities of liquids in laboratories. A pipette has a volume scale and, as a rule, pipette bulbs are used as droppers for liquids. Both sorts of pipettes are calibrated for fluids with a temperature of 20°C and for time of outflow (signified by "Ex."). If needed, times of outflow are indicated on the pipettes.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>erlenmeyerkolben.jpg</picture>
		<name>Erlenmeyer Flask</name>
		<desc>An Erlenmeyer flask, named after the chemist Emil Erlenmeyer (1825-1909), is different to a beaker in that it comes with an inverted conical base and a cylindrical neck. There are different types of Erlenmeyer flasks for laboratory applications: the narrow neck and wide neck forms. Depending on the application the flask may have precision grinding to allow good connection to other containers.
			&lt;br&gt;
			The narrow neck reduces the risk of fluid escaping, especially when boiling or during reactions which agitate the contents.
			&lt;br&gt;
			An Erlenmeyer flask is useful for mixing fluids or accelerating reactions by stirring or shaking, for example. The Erlenmeyer flask is particularly suited for a magnetic stirrer, since it can be placed directly on the stirring platform. A round-bottomed flask, by contrast, must be placed on a cork ring on the stirring platform.
</desc>

	</item>
	<item>
		<picture></picture>
		<name>Ultrasonic Bath</name>
		<desc>For some chemical reactions it is important that the solvent is gas free. To achieve this the reaction vessel is put for some time into a ultrasonic bath. Due to the high sound frequency, the vapor locks peel away and ascend. This procedure is called out-gassing.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>waage.jpg</picture>
		<name>Scales</name>
		<desc>In a laboratory, very precise quantities of reagents often have to be weighed out. High precision scales can measure masses down to 1/10000 gram. As such, they stand on granite blocks to avoid vibrations and are protected against changes in airflow by a dome.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>destillierbruecke.jpg</picture>
		<name>Distillation bridge</name>
		<desc>One means of separating a mixture is to use distillation. In this setting, a distillation bridge acts as a conduit between the two pots. One pot contains the mixture to be separated, and through heating, a gas forms which is lead through the bridge. At the end of the bridge the gas phase is condensed and drips into a round flask. Typically, the bridge is cooled by return flow. Also, there is often a thermometer for controlling the temperature of the distillation bridge.</desc>
	</item>
	<!-- proofreaders: start here! -->
	<item>
		<picture>kolbenprober.png</picture>
		<name>Syringe</name>
		<desc>A syringe consists of two parts, a glass tube and a plunger, both normally made of glass. Gasses flow into the glass tube, and as the syringe is a closed system, the plunger moves outwards. This can be used to measure the volume of a reaction.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>verteiler.jpg</picture>
		<name>Separation Beaker</name>
		<desc>First, four small caps are placed at the four ends of the separation beaker. Then, whilst distilling, the beaker is turned by 60 degrees after a certain temperate has been reached. In doing so, at the end of the distillation, all four caps contain a specific liquid, depending on the boiling point of the liquid distilled.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>brenner.jpg</picture>
		<name>Burner</name>
		<desc>There are several types of burners; this picture shows a Teclu-Burner. Each type of burner has specific uses, and they vary in peak temperature and overall heating capacity.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>abzug.jpg</picture>
		<name>Extractor Hood</name>
		<desc>Extractor hoods are used to filter out gases from chemical reactions. The air, once cleaned, is pumped outside of the building.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>thermometer2.jpg</picture>
		<name>Contact Thermometer</name>
		<desc>Contact thermometers differ from regular thermometers in that they are connected to a heating coil, and are hence able to both sense and control the current temperature. In doing so, they allow experiments to be performed under a constant temperature. Contact thermometers work using a negative feedback loop: once the desired temperature has been reached, the heating coil is deactivated; when the temperature falls, the heating coil is reactivated.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>halter.jpg</picture>
		<name>Clamps</name>
		<desc>Laboratory clamps make it easier to hold many kinds of tools.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>phpapier.jpg</picture>
		<name>Indicator Paper</name>
		<desc>There are multiple ways of measuring the pH value of a solution, one of which is to use indicator paper. Indicator paper changes color depending on the pH of the solution applied to it, and by comparing to a chart a fairly accurate measure of the solution's pH can be obtained. If a more accurate measure is needed, a glass electrode can be used, which works by measuring the conductivity of the solution.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>trichter.jpg</picture>
		<name>Short-Stem Funnel</name>
		<desc>A funnel can be used to fill a narrow-necked vessel with a liquid or fine powder.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture></picture>
		<name>Buret</name>
		<desc>Burets are used to titrate liquids. A buret is filled with a specific volume of a liquid, and placed beneath it is a container such as an Erlenmeyer flask. By opening the valve on the buret, the liquid in the container will then be titrated. High-quality burets have a venting mechanism with which they can be very easily refilled with the exact volume for which the buret is calibrated.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>becherglas.jpg</picture>
		<name>Beaker</name>
		<desc>Beakers can be used for many tasks. For instance, they are used to store chemicals and to perform chemical reactions. They are often also used for titrations.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture>dsc.jpg</picture>
		<name>DSC (Differential Scanning Calorimeter)</name>
		<desc>A DSC measures the heat flow volume of a compound. This value is very specific for every kind of matter, and thus a DSC can be used to identify chemicals or to describe them.</desc>
	</item>
	<item>
		<picture></picture>
		<name>Dewar Vessel</name>
		<desc>A Dewar vessel (or Dewar flask), named after the physicist Sir James Dewar (1842-1923), is a double-walled vacuum flask, designed to provide good thermal insulation. As such, they are useful for keeping liquids cool or warm. One well-known example of a Dewar vessel is a Thermos flask.</desc>
	</item>
</tools>
